<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Anton Karlsson</title>
    <link>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Anton Karlsson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 05:08:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DDS Validator</title>
      <link>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/dds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 05:08:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/dds/</guid>
      <description>DDS ValidatorIntroductionI started this project during pre-production of our first game project.I saw it as a challenge for myself to refresh my programming and create something useful for the projects at The Game Assembly to come.It&#39;s easy to use and highlights problematic files not utilizing the DDS formats strengths.After receiving some feedback I decided to also integrate Perforce into the program, which proved to be a valuable opportunity to learn more about Perforce and its accompanied API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic River Shader</title>
      <link>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/water/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 05:08:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/water/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic River ShaderIntroductionI set out to create a dynamic river shader, which would bend around intersecting objects.The idea came from some previous experimenting I&#39;ve done in the past using Distance Fields in Unreal, primarily blending edges between landscapes and intersecting objects.I decided to package the shader in an all-in-one blueprint featuring a custom spline for ease-of-use by a designer.Features• Real-time dynamic river shader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foliage Swapper</title>
      <link>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/foliage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 05:08:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/foliage/</guid>
      <description>Foliage SwapperIntroductionThe initial idea arose from wanting leaves falling from individual trees, which would mean the use of foliage actors.However, having an entire forest of foliage actors would not be feasible.And so this project was born, to swap between cheap instanced static meshes for more expensive actors within a set radius of the player.This way I could fully utilize Unreal&#39;s instanced static mesh system to reduce the amount of draw calls, but with the added benefit of having normal actors close to the player where it matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panjshir</title>
      <link>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/panjshir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 05:08:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/panjshir/</guid>
      <description>Panjshir, AfghanistanIntroductionI started this project as a challenge to create a large and detailed world (16.8km2).I decided on the realistic, tactical shooter Squad, because of it&#39;s large level sizes and the use of Unreal Engine 4.This proved to come with both pros and cons, but I will talk more about that further in.The level itself is heavily inspired by Panjshir, a mountainous province in northern Afghanistan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Way of the Turtle</title>
      <link>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/turtle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 05:08:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karlsson-anton.github.io/portfolio/turtle/</guid>
      <description>Way of the TurtleIntroductionYou follow the adventure of the turtle couple Mr and Mrs Turtle, now shipwrecked on a tropical island after a huge storm.Not all turtles can swim you know...You are tasked with dealing with a crazy wizard in exchange for a way off the island.I joined the team at Illusion Labs in the very early stages of development of Way of the Turtle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
